<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>about on marcopuccini@enea</title>
    <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/</link>
    <description>Recent content in about on marcopuccini@enea</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 08:59:17 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 10:06:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/publications/</guid>
      <description>2019 [1] M.Puccini, S. Migliori, F. Iannone, and M. Mongelli. 2019. &amp;ldquo;Survey of the Modern Database Technologies.&amp;rdquo; RT/2019/13/ENEA. ENEA.
[2] IMEKO, ed. 2019. Proceedings of the 2019 Imeko Tc-4 International Conference on Metrology for Archaeology and Cultural Heritage.
[3] M., Mongelli, Chellini G., Migliori S., Perozziello A., Pierattini S., Puccini M., and Cosma A. 2019. &amp;ldquo;Photogrammetry and Structured Light: Comparison and Integration of Techniques in Survey of the Corsini Throne at Corsini Gallery in Rome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>contats</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/contacts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 09:27:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/contacts/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Marco Puccini
 ENEA
TERIN - Energy Technologies and Renewables Department
ICT - Information Communication Technologies Division
HPC - High Performance Computing Lab
mail: marco.puccini@enea.it
site: www.afs.enea.it/puccini/
address: Lungotevere Thaon di Revel, 76 00196 ROMA Italia, first floor, room 104
repositories:
- gitlab@enea
- github
GPG:
- key: marcopuccini.pub
- fingerprint: 592A 21A1 64EB C026 6F85 4B88 083B 9D40 B84D 6BEC</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 08:59:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/about/</guid>
      <description>Облетев Землю в корабле-спутнике, я увидел, как прекрасна наша планета. Люди, будем хранить и преумножать эту красоту, а не разрушать её!
 Y.A.Gagarin   A (very) short presentation I&amp;rsquo;ve a MSc in Physics. Currently i&amp;rsquo;m involved in projects in the area of Heritage Sciences, in particular on 3D technologies (photogrammetry, SfM, rendering) and Big Data infrastructures (NoSQL DBs, distribuited platforms, IoT) for Cultural Heritage. My scientific interests are also:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>rafael</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/rafael/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/rafael/</guid>
      <description>Rafael </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>openiacs</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/openiacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/openiacs/</guid>
      <description>OpenIACS </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>enea-ceph</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/ceph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/ceph/</guid>
      <description>Ceph </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mia-fashion</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/miafashion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/miafashion/</guid>
      <description>M.I.A. Fashion M.I.A. Fashion (link in italian), Models and Solutions for Artificial Intelligence in the Luxury Fashion sector, is a project that aims to design and develop an ICT platform to support business of an importat luxury fashion company. The final objective of the project is to create a hybrid digital ecosystem, identifying the right technological trade-off that allows to take full advantage of the opportunities presented by the technical-scientific innovation related to artificial intelligence systems aiming to:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>covid19-datalake</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/covid19datalake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/covid19datalake/</guid>
      <description>Covid19 datalake Due to the Covid19 emergency, a huge number of projects and interest on related data has grown up. I&amp;rsquo;m involved on building up a datalake of a wide range of data linked to the Covid19 pandemic. I started to collect both data on Italy and World cases spread from the official italian Protezione Civile data repository and the global Johns Hopkins repository(https://github.com/CSSEGISandData/COVID-19). Moreover i started a tweets collection on selected hashtags to build up a huge set of documents (tweets) to allow possile future sentiment analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ikaros</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/ikaros/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/ikaros/</guid>
      <description>Ikaros </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ecodigit</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/ecodigit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/ecodigit/</guid>
      <description>Ecodigit Ecodigit was a project funded by the Regione Lazio for the DTC (District of Technologies and Culture) Centre of Excellence. It aims to project and develop the middleware component of the DTC digital ecosystem for cultural heritage. In particular ENEA was invloved to build up the Proof of Concept. It started in the November of 2018 and ended in the January of 2020. The main task was to build up a software component to make interoperable and dynamic the DTC graph of knowledge with advanced visualizations services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>enea-mongodb</title>
      <link>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/eneamongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.afs.enea.it/puccini/projects/eneamongodb/</guid>
      <description>ENEA mongoDB Among the big field of noSQL databases, mongoDB is the most widely used open source technology of his type, especially for Big Data storage and mnagment. ENEA start a collaboration with me to evaluate such technology and to build up a cluster installation of the Community Edition. Due to the common CAP theorem tradeoffs, mongoDB has a complex architecture to guarantee Consistency and (of course) Partition failures, with an high ratio of Accessibility too.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
